Dying of the Light is a thriller, drama film directed by Paul Schrader.
Evan Lake, a veteran CIA agent, has been ordered to retire.
But when his protégé uncovers evidence that Lake's nemesis, the terrorist Banir, has resurfaced, Lake
goes rogue, embarking on a perilous, intercontinental mission to eliminate his sworn enemy.
Evan Lake, played by Nicolas Cage.
Milton Schultz, played by Anton Yelchin.
Muhammad Banir, played by Alexander Karim.
Michelle Zuberain, played by Irène Jacob.
Aasim, played by Aymen Hamdouchi.
Mbui, played by Tomiwa Edun.
Dying of the Light is a 2014 American spy film,
written and directed by Paul Schrader.
It stars Nicolas Cage as an ex-CIA agent suffering from dementia who is on a personal mission
to track down and kill a terrorist who had tortured him two decades earlier.
Anton Yelchin and Irène Jacob also feature in the cast.
Dying of the Light was released theatrically and through VOD formats by Lionsgate on
December 5, 2014 to extremely negative reviews from film critics.
Schrader was denied final-cut privilege by the studio, who
heavily reedited the footage without his consent.
Schrader and his principal cast subsequently disowned the
released version of the film and campaigned against it.
The film explores themes of central intelligence agency
(cia), espionage, retirement, terrorism.
The tone is emotional and intense.